<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wiki.ctfg.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/basics/</guid><description>When playing a CTF, you are on the look out for flags. A flag usually looks something like this:
1 flag{some_message} There is a standardized format of flag{.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/asking-forensics-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/asking-forensics-questions/</guid><description>Asking Forensics Questions So you are looking at some piece of evidence. Evidence could be anything from a website, to an image, to even simply a piece of text.</description></item><item><title>Ciphers</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/ciphers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/ciphers/</guid><description>Substitution Ciphers What is a Substitution Cipher? A Substitution cipher is a way of encrypting data, where every occurrence of specific letter from the alphabet within the plaintext you supply, is substituted by another character from the alphabet.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Intro</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/intro/</guid><description>Cryptography is the practice of securing communication from third-party access, ensuring that only the intended recipient can access the message. It involves the use of mathematical algorithms to encode and decode information, converting it into a secret code that is unreadable to anyone except the intended recipient.</description></item><item><title>Encoding</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/encoding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/encoding/</guid><description>ASCII ASCII or the American Standard Code for Information Interchange is an encoding scheme designed to represent simple text characters on computers.</description></item><item><title>Encryption</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/encryption/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/encryption/</guid><description>Encryption v.s Encoding Encryption and encoding are often confused. Encoding is a way to convert data from one format to another.</description></item><item><title>Forensics Intro</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/intro/</guid><description>Forensics is the art of recovering the digital trail left on a computer. There are plently of methods to find data which is seemingly deleted, not stored, or worse, covertly recorded.</description></item><item><title>General Resources</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/general/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/general/</guid><description> https://ctfs.github.io/resources/ https://github.com/swisskyrepo/PayloadsAllTheThings https://ctf101.org https://ctf-wiki.mahaloz.re/ (very extensive) https://book.hacktricks.xyz/</description></item><item><title>Hashing</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/hashing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/crypto/hashing/</guid><description>What is Hashing? Hashing is a super neat example of cryptography, with many important uses in data integrity. The algorithm used when hashing takes any input data (known as the plaintext) - such as a message, a file, a password - and produces a fixed size ciphertext; which is a hash value, most commonly referred to has a hash.</description></item><item><title>Linux Intro</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/linux/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/linux/intro/</guid><description>What is Linux? Linux is an operating system, just like Windows or Mac OS. It is a free and open source operating system, meaning that anyone can use it, modify it, and distribute it.</description></item><item><title>Solving MCPSHSF on a Chromebook</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/chromebooks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/chromebooks/</guid><description>Although it is possible to solve MCPSHSF challenges on a Chromebook, it is difficult. This is because Chromebooks do not support the use of virtual machines, which are necessary for solving many challenges.</description></item><item><title>What are file formats?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-are-file-formats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-are-file-formats/</guid><description>File Extensions are not the sole way to identify the type of a file, files have certain leading bytes called file signatures which allow programs to parse the data in a consistent manner.</description></item><item><title>What is a hex editor?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-a-hex-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-a-hex-editor/</guid><description>A hexadecimal (hex) editor (also called a binary file editor or byte editor) is a computer program you can use to manipulate the fundamental binary data that constitutes a computer file.</description></item><item><title>What is disk imaging?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-disk-imaging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-disk-imaging/</guid><description>A forensic image is an electronic copy of a drive (e.g. a hard drive, USB, etc.). It’s a bit-by-­bit or bitstream file that’s an exact, unaltered copy of the media being duplicated.</description></item><item><title>What is memory forensics?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-memory-forensics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-memory-forensics/</guid><description>There are plenty of traces of someone&amp;rsquo;s activity on a computer, but perhaps some of the most valuble information can be found within memory dumps, that is images taken of RAM.</description></item><item><title>What is metadata?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-metadata/</guid><description>Metadata is data about data. Different types of files have different metadata. The metadata on a photo could include dates, camera information, GPS location, comments, etc.</description></item><item><title>What is steganography?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-steganography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-steganography/</guid><description>Stegonagraphy is the practice of hiding data in plain sight. Stegonagraphy is often embedded in images or audio.
You could send a picture of a cat to a friend and hide text inside.</description></item><item><title>What is wireshark?</title><link>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-wireshark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.ctfg.io/forensics/what-is-wireshark/</guid><description>Wireshark is a network protocol analyzer which is often used in CTF challenges to look at recorded network traffic. Wireshark uses a filetype called PCAP to record traffic.</description></item></channel></rss>