<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cryptoes on</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in Cryptoes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ciphers</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/ciphers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/ciphers/</guid><description>Substitution Ciphers What is a Substitution Cipher? A Substitution cipher is a way of encrypting data, where every occurrence of specific letter from the alphabet within the plaintext you supply, is substituted by another character from the alphabet.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Intro</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/intro/</guid><description>Cryptography is the practice of securing communication from third-party access, ensuring that only the intended recipient can access the message. It involves the use of mathematical algorithms to encode and decode information, converting it into a secret code that is unreadable to anyone except the intended recipient.</description></item><item><title>Encoding</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/encoding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/encoding/</guid><description>ASCII ASCII or the American Standard Code for Information Interchange is an encoding scheme designed to represent simple text characters on computers.</description></item><item><title>Encryption</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/encryption/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/encryption/</guid><description>Encryption v.s Encoding Encryption and encoding are often confused. Encoding is a way to convert data from one format to another.</description></item><item><title>Hashing</title><link>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/hashing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.xctf.io/crypto/hashing/</guid><description>What is Hashing? Hashing is a super neat example of cryptography, with many important uses in data integrity. The algorithm used when hashing takes any input data (known as the plaintext) - such as a message, a file, a password - and produces a fixed size ciphertext; which is a hash value, most commonly referred to has a hash.</description></item></channel></rss>